mapometer.com 2019-10-24

# Mapometer privacy policy

At mapometer.com, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is a description of the types of personal information we receive and collect when you visit mapometer.com, and how we safeguard your information.  We will never sell or otherwise share your personal information with third parties.

Any questions or concerns about data privacy may be addressed to [privacy@mapometer.com](mailto:privacy@mapometer.com).

## Your rights

Following the introduction of the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR), you have a number rights giving you control over your personal data held by any organisation.

  * Right to withdraw consent for any particular use of your data.
  * Right to rectification. If you believe any data we hold about you is incorrect, you may ask to have it corrected.
  * Right to be forgotten. You may request to have the data we hold about removed from our systems.
  * You have a right to know what data we hold about you. You may make a Subject Access Request (SAR) to obtain a copy of all of the data we hold on you. 

## Our responsibilities

The GDPR also imposes responsibilites on the organisation holding your data.

  * We must build our systems with privacy by design. This includes taking reasonable steps to ensure the security of data storage and data access.
  * We must seek afirmative consent for any new use of you data.
  * We may not hold data for any longer than is necessary to perform the uses for which we have consent. We will remove all data relating to unused accounts. An account is currently considered unused if it has had no activity for 4 years.
  * We are oblidged to promptly report any data breaches to the Information Commissioners Office.

## The data we collect.

### Account information

Your account information includes any and all data you yourself enter into our website whilst using it. This may include an email address and username, sports routes and activities and user settings. This data can be edited or deleted by you using your account pages on the website.

The routes and activities you save on our system cannot, by default, be viewed by other users of the website. If you wish certain routes to be included in the route search, your may make these routes public when you create them, or later from your route list page. If you wish to share a route or activity with others, either by social media or email, you'll also need to make the route publicly viewable.

The website allows users to share content with others via an email contact list. We never directly contact anyone you add to your contact list. These people only receive emails when you share a route with them. Anyone with whom you share routes via email will be given the chance to opt-out of receiving emails from you (to protect their privacy).

The current working copies of your account information are stored on our webserver. Your data are stored on a local database and also on the local file system (GPX files) of the server. We also keep off-site backups (on Amazon S3) of the database and file system for 90 days. It should be noted that, while deleting your account or elements of your data will have immediate effect on the live server, it is not practical to remove individual pieces of data from these archived backups. Deleted accounts or data may therefore remain in archived backups for up to 90 days after deletion from the live server.

### Social media information

Our website allows users to login to the site, or to share routes with others, using some social media accounts (Facebook, Twitter, Google+). If you have used any of these facilities we will have a record of your id, username and email address on these platforms.

### PayPal account information

If you have been generous enough to donate or subscribe to our website, we will create be a record of our interaction with PayPal to process this payment. This payment record will include your PayPal payer-id and registered email address, as well as the amount paid and the date of the transaction. The payment records will be retained by us even if you request to have your other data removed from our systems. This is necessary use, required by taxation and money laundering regulations.

### Server logs

As with most other websites, we collect and may use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as BT or AOL), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Chrome), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site. This data is not routinely associated with you or your account, but may occasionally be used for debugging purposes. Server logs are retained for a maximum of 6 months.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

We do use cookies (and browser local storage) to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.  This includes the ability to login automatically. 

We also use third party advertisements on mapometer.com to support our site.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

### DoubleClick DART cookies

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests ("interest based targeting"). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses "non personally identifiable information". It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx 

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.
